I want to learn more
about Buddhism
I don't know that much about Buddhism
and can be considered a newbie.
So I was wondering
if there is a good way
to learn more about Buddhism.
For people like us,
can you advise us on how we can get
interested and closer to Buddhism?
When you say Buddhism,
there are two types.
There's Buddhism as a religion
and there's the Buddha's dharma as truth.
We generally say Buddhism
but there is Buddhism
within the context of religion
And then there is Dharma
within the context of truth.
So what is Buddhism as a religion?
It's similar to Christianity.
Some people go to church to pray to God.
Others go to a Buddhist temple to pray
to the Buddha and ask for good fortune.
This is Buddhism as a religion.
Dharma as truth implies that
a pure minded person is a Buddhist monk.
Simply shaving his head and wearing
grey attire does not make one a monk.
His mind has to be pure.
Likewise, a temple is not
some special building
but a place
where pure minded people reside.
So today, if we talk about
how to make money,
how to be successful,
who is right or wrong,
this place is a lecture hall.
But if we talk about
how people can be happier,
this place is a temple.
From the perspective of truth,
Truth exists
beyond the boundaries of religions
such as Buddhism or Christianity.
So if you want to approach
Buddhism as religion,
you can go to a temple nearby.
If you want to approach
dharma as truth, you can do this.
Like the previous example,
If you hate your husband
because he is too stingy,
this is an unenlightened thinking.
You can instead think that
being frugal is good.
You can tell youself,
"Eventually, my son and I will be spending
the money he saves.
So, the more he saves, the better."
You can take a situation
you viewed negatively in the past
and see it in a positive light.
This is dharma as truth.
Let me explain this
according to Buddhist principles.
Thinking, "That person is bad.
My husband is bad."
is called Conception (Saṃjna).
A negative conception in this case.
Realizing that in truth,
he is not a bad person,
is emptying your conception.
Actually, conception does not exist.
Saying that person is bad is Form (Rūpa).
Saying that person is not bad
is Emptiness (Śūnyatā).
Thus, the phrase "Form is emptiness"
appears in the Heart Sutra.
So, when the previous lady said that
her husband is stingy and bad,
I say, "Isn't the money yours at the end?"
or "isn't it better
to be frugal than spendy?"
As we make these exchanges,
she may realize that he is
not such a bad person after all.
This is to know
the emptiness of all things.
There's no such a thing
as an innately bad person.
So when she starts
to think positively about him,
she may realize that he is
a good person after all.
But emptiness does not mean
there is nothing.
When we think positively,
others become good.
This is "Emptiness itself is form."
Instead of talking about
form is this and emptiness is that,
when the lady said her husband is bad,
I said how he isn't that bad.
This is the principle
behind such conversation.
So how do you feel now?
Are you happier living with
a stingy husband
or living with a frugal husband?
You are happier living with
a frugal husband.
If you say your husband is stingy,
he becomes a bad person
and if you say he
is frugal, he becomes a good person.
If your husband is a good person,
then your son is a good son.
Why? Because he is
the son of a good father.
When you say your husband is a bad person,
your son is also a bad person.
Why? Because he is
the son of a bad person.
Like father like son,
so he must be bad too. Right?
Such things is what makes us unhappy.
You can't make yourself happy
by resolving to be happy.
Your happiness begins
when you change your negative views
about your husband into positive ones.
This is studying Dharma.
You can study the dharma without
using Buddhist terminology.
Then, could we find such principles
in the Bible? We can.
Truth exists beyond the boundaries of
Christianity or Buddhism.
From a religious aspect,
Christians and Buddhists
cannot avoid conflict
because they will argue over
who is right and who is better.
My conversation with you today will be
about Dharma from
the perspective of truth.
You can go to a temple to study the dharma,
but you can also study at home.
What did that lady say?
She said she hated her husband,
but since she started watching
YouTube videos of my dharma talks,
she is more at peace.
This mean that she is a little happier
or, at least, less miserable.
So if your mindset changes
watching videos at home,
the place where you are sitting
at that moment is a temple.
So, one method to study the dharma is
to attend dharma talks
like this as often as you can.
Or you can join one of
the small study groups
that study the dharma since it is hard
to study consistently by yourself.
Christians are also welcome to
join the study groups.
From the realm of the dharma as truth,
it doesn’t matter whether
you go to church or temple
and whether you have a religion or not.
It's a place to study your mind.
So take a pamphlet on your way out
to see where the study group meets.
You can attend a session
and if you like it,
you can continue to study there.
If you don't like it,
you are free to stop attending.
You can study at home by
yourself watching Youtube videos.
If that isn't enough, you can go
and meet a Buddhist monk
or go and study at a
Buddhist temple nearby.
The truth exists in your everyday life.
So, you don't have to think of
it as something very difficult.
Thank you very much.